Francis Kim

_

Software Developer

francis.kim@yale.edu (859)-494-0978 francis-m-kim.github.io LinkedIn · GitHub

Projects

Skills

Ruby, Rails, SQL, jQuery, JavaScript, React.js, Flux, Git, HTML5, CSS, MaxMSP, Processing **Cruddyreads:** A full stack web app inspired by Goodreads, built with Rails and React.

- Permits Twitter login through OmniAuth for a seamless user experience.
- Uses AWS3 to store images. Remote hosting in the cloud allows for future scalability.
- React lifecycle methods and Flux architecture ensure that application data and rendering are in sync.

Quindici: A browser game inspired by the classic Game of 15 puzzle, using an image or GIF background.

- All aspects of the game are customizable: board dimensions, difficulty, and background can all be changed by the user.
- Uses jQuery listeners and CSS hover-overs to respond to user interaction and change game state.
- Employs a custom algorithm to ensure that the game begins only with winnable tile positions.

myQuery: A lightweight JavaScript library for DOM manipulation

- Common DOM tasks like adding or modifying HTML are simplified by wrapping elements in a JavaScript object which abstracts away mundane complexities.
- Entire library weighs in at less than 10 kilobytes, so as not to affect page load time.

Education

App Academy, 2016

12-week full-stack development bootcamp with < 5% acceptance rate

Yale University School of Music, M.M., Organ Performance, GPA: 3.85, 2013-15

- Recipient of Full Merit Scholarship and Fellowship
- · Recipient of Charles Ives Prize for Organ

Catholic University of America, Graduate studies in Philosophy, 2007–08

University of Louisville, B.A., Philosophy, GPA: 3.65, 2005–07

Oberlin College Conservatory of Music, Piano Performance, 2002-05

Recipient of Conservatory Dean's Scholarship

Experience

Associate Music Director at St. Pius X Church, Scarsdale, NY, 2015–16 Directed the choir and played organ for a congregation of > 1,000. Taught music lessons to parish children.

Instructor at the Yale School of Music, New Haven, CT, 2013-15

Taught weekly organ lessons to Yale students. Students received school credit for their lessons.

Director of Music at St. Stephen Martyr Church, Washington, DC, 2010–12 Played organ for all services and conducted a choir of 8 paid singers. Led the process of hiring new singers.